<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>antuki.github.io</title>
    <link>/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on antuki.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <copyright>antuki. Powered by [blogdown](https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown)/[Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme based on Icarus by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice) with modifications by [antuki](https://antuki.github.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Your opinion of the packages COGugaison and CARTElette</title>
      <link>/en/2019/11/08/opinion_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/11/08/opinion_package/</guid>
      <description>This survey aims to better know the users of the two R packages COGugaison and CARTElette, which make possible to manage the evolution of administrative divisions over time in France, in databases and map layers.
Thank you very much for your participation which will contribute to the improvement of these packages!
Access the form
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a summer 2020 internship</title>
      <link>/en/2019/10/19/internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/10/19/internship/</guid>
      <description>🎤Looking for a 2020 Summer #internship in #DataScience. Back in school @ENSAEparis after five years of professional experience in French official statistics. Preferably in 🇺🇸🇨🇦🇦🇺 Many personal #rstats projects on my github and LinkedIn. https://t.co/NZP2I7o2LT pic.twitter.com/8PXNbCUFvV
&amp;mdash; antuki (@antuki13) September 21, 2019  After 5 years of professional experience in official statistics, I am back in school to complete my training to become a Senior Officer for the French National Institute of Statistics and Economic Studies (INSEE), after recently passing the internal competitive exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post full of love :blue_heart: thanks to emojifont package</title>
      <link>/en/2017/10/08/emojifont/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/10/08/emojifont/</guid>
      <description>A first article to celebrate the creation of this blog thanks to Hugo and blogdown. I can now create posts (in French and / or English) with one click from R.
It is also an opportunity to share with you my discovery of the emojifont package which allows to add small images to our ggplots. Thank you @guangchuangyu!
#install.packages(&amp;quot;emojifont&amp;quot;)library(emojifont)## Warning: le package &amp;#39;emojifont&amp;#39; a été compilé avec la version R 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Packages</title>
      <link>/en/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/packages/</guid>
      <description>COGugaison is an R package for manipulating french spatial databases produced at different dates
The administrative divisions of France (communes – counties – regions, departments…) change over time. Every year, some french territories change their codes, or names, merge or divide.
The COGugaison R package is based on the french official geographic code (COG) produced each year by the french National Institute of Statistics and Economic Studies (Insee). It has the objective of manipulating spatial databases produced at different dates by providing the list of existing towns and their history since fifty years and useful functions for transforming databases into geographic codes of other years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>/en/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Below my different talks. Clic on the image to see the slides !
useR! conference Toulouse july 2019 
Tutorial Spatial data and cartography for satRday Paris february 2019  
with Etienne Côme and Timothée Giraud.
Updated version of the workshop in september 2018 for Summer school Massive spatial data of the LabEx DynamiTe: lecture and exercises.
7th French R Meeting july 2018 
RLadies Paris meet-up march 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>À propos</title>
      <link>/en/apropos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/apropos/</guid>
      <description>hello !
My name is Kim, i&amp;rsquo;m a female statistician and I love doing R when I&amp;rsquo;m lonely at home.
The objective of this blog is to share with you my R discoveries when I have time (some periods are more effective than others) and talk about developers or reseachers works and there super cool packages that I find interesting. I also love open data so I may also indicate some cool data to manipulate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>